LAURENCE PUTRA FRANSLAY

laurenceputra@outlook.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/laurenceputra

A versatile engineer with a knack for picking up new technologies on the fly, I am currently in my first role as an engineering manager. I have worked on, and led teams across huge variety of technologies, from mobile to web to servers. It is my core belief that strong fundamentals allow me to pick up new technologies rapidly.

EXPERIENCE

DEC 2016 - NOW

DEVOPS LEAD, SINGAPORE POWER LTD

- Lead and manage the DevOps team in the role of DevOps lead
- Push for processes to be codified and automated through a docker based Jenkins for auditability and repeatability
- Set up common infra across the company, including a central log server
- Part of a major DC Relocation project, serving on the command center
- Temporary 3-month stint as Android Lead to push a delayed android project to production
- Sits on SP's security council, providing feedback from a DevOps and Infra point of view

APR 2016 - OCT 2016

SENIOR ENGINEER, NUGIT PTE. LTD

- Lead the infrastructure team
- Planned and executed upgrades on outdated database systems
- Introduced Salt Stack to codify server setup and automate app deployments
- Set up central monitoring and logging platform to improve visibility to the engineers
- Monitored and optimized slow database queries through data restructuring and indexing, increasing performance by more than 10x
- Set up company network

MAR 2014 - MAR 2016

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, PAYPAL PTE. LTD

- Delivered functionality on the legacy C and Java stacks to support business needs
- Built and maintained a bug dashboard to make bug reporting more transparent
- Worked on both PayPal's Android and iOS applications, including building infrastructure UI components for the Android App
- Developed NFC capability in Payments and Card Reading
- Core Team of internal automation framework based on Capybara
- Maintained internal gem proxy
- Lead and drove the outreach initiatives to build branding within developer circles
- Grew the outreach team from 3 to 15 volunteers

MAY 2013 - FEB 2014

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, BILLPIN PTE. LTD

- Led the integration of the database of a startup acquired by the company
- Rewrote architecture of the backend to reduce load on users' devices and paving the way to support more features, including other currencies
- Identified key business metrics and build dashboard to visualize them
- Optimized load times by more than 20x on query intensive pages
- Managed all the servers with Salt Stack

EDUCATION

MAY 2013

BACHELOR OF COMPUTING IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SINGAPORE

- Focused on Distributed System and Security
- Notable modules taken includes Distributed Systems offered at the Masters Level, and Software Engineering on Evolving Platforms
- Coreteam member of NUSHackers from Aug 2010 Sept 2012, driving the hacker culture within the school
- Had a taste of liberal arts as part of Tembusu College
- Graduated with Second (Lower) Class Honors.

OUTSIDE OF WORK

NOV 2014 - NOW

CORETEAM, IAMTALENTEDSG

- Run programs in partnership with Community Development Councils in Singapore targeted at Youth at Risk
- Intent of the program is to inspire these Youth at Risk, giving them confidence and a sense of purpose
- Run more than 10 different workshops in parallel every year for the youths to try out

JULY 2011 - NOV 2014

MAIN ORGANIZER, GEEKCAMPSG

- Organized GeekcampSG, then one of the largest tech conferences in Singapore
- Grew the community from 200 geeks in 2011 to 1500 attendees in 2013
- Invited Dr Vivian Balakrishnan for a keynote in 2014

2